edaboard.com 2018-06-30

# Forum for Electronics - Forum Rules

****General Rules****

  * Use Code tags
  * Select the proper section and don’t post duplicates
  * Use descriptive titles
  * Blog content
  * Uploaded files
  * Do not post or request copyright material
  * Don’t create multiple accounts
  * Thread bumping is not allowed
  * Do not spam or self-promote in the forums
  * Advertising is intended for Electronics Design related products only
  * Do not contact users asking for help or to advertise
  * Remain respectful of other users, moderators and administrators at all times
  * Misusing report functionality
  * Don't intrude in threads with different subject or reopen very old threads
  * Post content that is not allowed
  * Signatures
  * Groups

**\-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------**  
**Use CODE/SYNTAX tags**  
Code or logs posted in messages should be enclosed in code tags, this limits the space they occupy and makes them easier to read and understand by showing indents and highlighting keywords. Please read [_this_](http://www.edaboard.com/announcements31.html) tutorial that explains how to apply them.

 **Select the proper section and don’t post duplicates**  
Please post your question in the proper forum section, this will help you get replies faster. If your question can fit in more than one category then select the section that seems more appropriate. If you're not sure where to post, ask a moderator first.  
Duplicates or cross posting are not allowed, avoid creating multiple threads with similar questions, ask all related questions in one thread.  
There are specific sections for education, jobs and business promotion so use them correctly and don’t post content that belongs in these sections to any other categories.

 **Use descriptive titles**  
Use proper descriptive titles related to the content of your post without adding useless prefix like "urgent" or "help me" or excessive punctuation like "...." or "!!!!" etc. Give a short summary of your problem IN THE SUBJECT . Titles like the following are considered completely useless and will result in the deletion of the thread and an infraction:

  * Help me
  * You must know the answer
  * Very urgent
  * I have a question
  * Stupid question
  * Newbie needs help

**Blog content**  
Blogs are not the place to advertise your website or business neither ask questions. Post there only articles or own ideas that you want show to others.

 **Uploaded files**  
Don’t upload files that are widely available in the internet and can be found easily like datasheets or application notes, this is a waste of valuable bandwidth, post a link instead.  
Also format your image attachments properly, use an image resolution that is easily readable, not too big or too small and use gif, png, or jpeg extension to reduce the size of the file.  
Avoid using bmp image format, it occupies a huge size compared to the formats described above and can’t be shown directly in a browser which is an additional inconvenience.  
If your code is long prefer to use a zip file to attach it in the post instead of directly posting it.  
Don’t upload your files to external servers and post the links, these files will be deleted after a while and the thread will become useless, attach your files in the post. Moderators **will delete** any posts that includes files uploaded to file sharing servers like Rapidshare, 4shared etc. Try to uploads compressed formats that are easily opened by different operating systems, zip is preferred over rar or 7zip and note that the attachments should never be password protected.

 **Do not share or request copyright material**  
Do not upload, attach, or otherwise post any copyrighted material which you are not free to redistribute (subject to the licensing terms of the specific item). If you have a question about having permission to post or attach a specific item, please ask a moderator. We do not condone nor accept posts pertaining to illegal activities such as hacking, cracking, *****, or spam.  
IEEE papers are also copyrighted and as such not allowed unless you have the author permission or are freely available, please read [_this_](http://www.edaboard.com/thread168924.html).

 **Do not create multiple accounts**  
Don’t create multiple accounts in order to bump your thread or give helpful ratings to yourself or your friends. Members found to have duplicate accounts will be banned **.**

 **Thread bumping is not allowed**  
Don't bump your thread with useless followups like “please help” or “no one” etc. and don’t be in a hurry to get a reply, be patient. If you have any additional info to provide (like results gathered after the posted question or additional info) then you are welcome to post them in order to explain better your problem.

 **Do not spam or self-promote in the forums**  
These forums define spam as unsolicited advertisement for goods, services and/or other web sites or posts with little, no or completely unrelated content.  
Do not spam the forums with links to your site or product, or try to self-promote your website, business or forums etc. Doing so is a waste of time, your account will be banned permanently and your posts will be deleted.  
Spamming also includes sending private messages to a large number of different users.  
If you intend to reply to a question with a content existing in your blog then you should include the content in the actual reply and provide an optional link to the article but not just a bare link. Do not search the forum for convenient question which match a content in your blog so that you can post a link and self-promote 

**Advertising is intended for Electronics Design related products only**  
Advertising is currently only allowed in the [_Business, Promotions, Advertising_](http://www.edaboard.com/forum43.html) section, it is not allowed in Albums, Groups, Biography, Location, Interests or any other place.  
Please note that you shouldn't post duplicate advertisements every few days.  
Do not post advertisements related to gadgets, personal computers, nutrition, medicine, fitness, web design etc.

 **Do not contact users asking for help or to advertise**  
Don't make requests for help in private using personal messages, create a thread in the forum so that other members can benefit from the posted answers.  
DO NOT ever send private messages to ANY user offering to sell services or products UNLESS the user ASKS you to contact them.  
If any user see this behaviour of "stealth" advertising / spam, please report the post.

 **Remain respectful of other users, moderators and administrators at all times**  
All posts should be professional and courteous. You have every right to disagree with your fellow community members and explain your perspective, however, you are not free to attack, degrade, insult, or otherwise belittle them or the quality of this community. It does not matter what title or power you hold in these forums, you are expected to obey this rule. Doing otherwise will get your account banned temporarily, or permanently if the situation becomes severe enough (this will be left to the discretion of the moderation team).

 **Misusing report functionality**  
The report post functionality is intended to report spam, advertising messages and problematic (harassment, fighting, or rude) posts. Don't use it without a reason or when you want to post messages, the report is not a reply button. Misuse of report will result in an warning or infraction.

 **Don't intrude in threads with different subject or reopen very old threads**  
Follow up questions should be related to the thread content, don’t intrude in an existing thread to ask a question with a subject unrelated to the thread content, create a new thread instead.  
Avoid reopening very old threads in order to reply or post a similar question, again it is more preferable to create a new thread.

 **Post content described below is not allowed**

  * Posting in any language other than English in any of the forum sections (forum, blogs, groups, signatures, etc).
  * Posting in CAPITAL letters, huge fonts (equivalent of shouting)..
  * “Thank you” posts are considered useless, If you want to thank a user then click the helpful hand icon found under the post or donate points.
  * h**p://www style links or any other form that is not clickable, use normal http://www links instead.
  * Technical abbreviations unless they are universally understood, they will confuse members and make it hard for them to understand what you mean.
  * SMS abbreviations, they make posts unreadable and prevent many users that don’t know English well enough to understand them. Type complete words.
  * Intentionally posting incorrect or flagrantly dangerous information
  * Meaningless threads, one word (or short) non-sense posts, or the such (e.g “I agree”).
  * Discussion of illegal activities such as software and music piracy and other intellectual property violations.
  * Excessive numbers of emoticons, large, small or coloured text, etc
  * Excessive punctuation (e.g. ! and ?) in topic titles or posts
  * Threads requesting to receive reply in private email
  * Offering to provide help as a paid service in non advertising section.
  * Discussions of politics, ethnicity, religion, or other divisive issues in any area.
  * Anything which is offensive, hateful, racist, sexist, discriminatory, obscene, vulgar or in violation of local or international laws.
  * Insulting posts, personal attacks or purposeless inflammatory posts.

**Signatures**  
Should BE polite and not offensive. Should be in English language. Should NOT have advertisements, link to other web site, email or images.  
Size limits: 4 lines. Font sizes above 2 are not allowed. (Blank lines count as lines.)

 **Groups**  
Group owners are responsible to apply the forum rules to the group sections and report any posts or behaviour that is against the rules.

 ** **FAQ****

 **What happens if I see a thread/post which has broken a rule?**  
Please report the thread/post to the moderators using the report link which appears in the right-hand corner under each post. This report will be sent to all moderators of that particular forum who will respond to the incident as quickly as possible.

 **I see something that is definitely spam. Should I do anything?**  
If you see someone posting advertisements which are irrelevant to the thread topic or simply any other form of spamming, please report the post by clicking the "Report post" button.  
Please **Do Not** post any replies to that message such as "Go away, idiot," or "You're stupid.", this only bumps the thread back to the top of the forum listing, and makes the spammer's post(s) visible for a longer period of time. Once you've reported the post or thread, a moderator will soon take care of it as needed.

 **What happens if I break a rule?**  
If you break a rule, then you will either be warned or banned. A ban of your user account may either be temporary or permanent. While a ban will normally involve only a ban of your user account, in extreme circumstances, it is possible to block your IP address from the forums.  
The administrators and moderators also have the right to edit, delete, move or close and thread or post as they see necessary, without prior warning.

 **Editing and Deleting Your Posts**  
The administrators have decided to prevent users from deleting their own posts. In the past, deleting the first post of a thread would delete the entire thread, making it impossible for others to be able to read and learn from the information posted. There is also a limited amount of time in which you are allowed to edit your post, after that the post can’t be edited.  
As a rule we do not remove or delete content from our forums so before you post consider this rule. If you don’t want to share a schematic or code then don’t post it but don’t expect to get help and then delete your post, users in the forum spend valuable time in order to reply in your post so this info should remain available for users that may have a similar question in the future.

 **Why do some usernames appear in blue or red text?**  
Any user who is an administrator or moderator will have their username appear in a bold, red font. This addition has been made to the forum to help make it obvious for new users to see who is in charge. A full list of the moderators and the forums they moderate is available[ _here_](http://www.edaboard.com/showgroups.php)

 **What are the consequences of warnings and infractions**  
Warnings serve as a reminder to you of the forum's rules which you are expected to understand and follow. When you break a rule then you receive a warning and if you keep breaking the rule then you get infraction points. 

**What are sticky threads?**  
'Sticky' threads are created by moderators or administrators, and remain 'stuck' to the top of the listing, even if they haven't had any posts recently. Their purpose is to keep important information visible and accessible at all times.

 **I get a "no permission error", what do I do?**  
This happens as you did not complete the registration process. To complete the registration you must use the activation link in the e-mail sent to you. This is to confirm the true identity of you. If you have not received a registration e-mail, look in the spam folder as sometimes the email is flagged as spam. If the e-mail has not been flagged as spam then please[ _request another activation e-mail_](http://www.edaboard.com/register.php?do=requestemail).

 **I forgot my password. What can I do?**  
If you forget your password, you can click on the '[ _Forgotten Your Password_](http://www.edaboard.com/login.php?do=lostpw) ' link. This will appear on any page that requires you to fill in your password.  
This link brings up a page where you should enter your registered email address. An email will be sent to that address shortly, with instructions for resetting your password.  
Since passwords are encrypted, there is no way to resend your original password. This option provides you with the ability to reset your password.  
You must be able to receive emails to your registered email address for this to work. You may need to check your spam filters and folder if you do not see this email in a few minutes.

 ** **Guidelines****

 **USE SEARCH FIRST!**  
There is a pretty good chance that unless you have some really odd or unique problem that it has been addressed on this forum before (or even hundreds of times before for some issues).  
Use the forum's search feature first to see if there are already some good threads on the subject. It's easy to search - just click the "Search" button at the top left of the page.

 **Be descriptive**  
Take the time to explain the problem you are facing properly and attach in the post any available code, schematic or other related content.  
Posting a huge code doesn’t help solve the problem, isolate the part where the problem is and provide info about the error message you get and the line number where it occurs.

 **Post content**  
Links to external sites can often become "dead" or broken when these external sites change their format or simply cease to exist, unfortunately there are already several cases of old threads that have become useless this way. The following measures will ensure the viability of the post, regardless of the state of external sites.  
When possible all posts should contain source code, simulation files, schematics, photos, etc with the appropriate credit for the source of these materials given. If the source code consists of multiple files or is simply too lengthy to be posted directly, it should be compressed and uploaded to the forum as an attachment.

 **Only you know what "doesn't work" means**  
Please tell us what your circuit or code is supposed to do and why it "doesn't work".When you come in and say "it doesn't work" or just "it has errors", that means NOTHING. There could be a million things wrong and no one will know where to look.

 **Signature and Avatar Guidelines**  
The contents of your sig must be acceptable for our community and shall not contain any profanity, vulgarity, or insults/disparaging comments to our community or its members. In addition, comments and/or advertising links are not allowed.

  * Keep your signature and avatar in good taste, the contents of your signature must be acceptable for the community: no vulgarity, lewd men/women, profanity or insults to other community members.
  * Animation should be kept to a minimum and both your signature and avatar shouldn't be too distracting.
  * Do not include spam, harassing links or affiliate links in your signature.

Any signature violating these rules will be considered spam, they will be deleted and the offending member will be addressed by our moderators.

 **Put your code in CODE or SYNTAX tags**  
When you include code in your posts you should always use **CODE** or **SYNTAX** tags, these tags limit the length of the code and show the indents properly so that the code is easier to read and doesn't occupy too much space. Please read this tutorial to learn how to use code tags.

 **Solved threads**  
Please mark your threads as solved when you have solved your problem so that other users know that you don’t need any more help. If you find the solution yourself please take the time to explain the solution so that other users have similar issues can benefit from it.

 **Replies**  
Please avoid replies like “google it” or “read the datasheet” or if you give such answers provide a couple of links or the specific chapter/page that the user should read.  
Don’t reply to posts when you can’t help with the asked question and don’t intrude in threads with a different subject or follow up with questions unrelated to the thread content.

**Terms and Conditions**  
If you continue to browse and use this website, you are agreeing to comply with and be bound by the following terms and conditions of use, which together with our privacy policy govern EDABOARD relationship with you in relation to this website. If you disagree with any part of these terms and conditions, please do not use our website. The term EDABOARD or 'us' or 'we' refers to the owner of the website. The term 'you' refers to the user or viewer of our website.  
The use of this website is subject to the following terms of use:  
1\. The content of the pages of this website is for your general information and use only. It is subject to change without notice.  
2\. Neither we nor any third parties provide any warranty or guarantee as to the accuracy, timeliness, performance, completeness or suitability of the information and materials found or offered on this website for any particular purpose. You acknowledge that such information and materials may contain inaccuracies or errors and we expressly exclude liability for any such inaccuracies or errors to the fullest extent permitted by law.   
3\. Your use of any information or materials on this website is entirely at your own risk, for which we shall not be liable. It shall be your own responsibility to ensure that any products, services or information available through this website meet your specific requirements.   
4\. This website contains material which is owned by or licensed to us. This material includes, but is not limited to, the design, layout, look, appearance and graphics. Reproduction is prohibited other than in accordance with the copyright notice, which forms part of these terms and conditions.   
5\. All trade marks reproduced in this website which are not the property of, or licensed to, the operator are acknowledged on the website.   
6\. Unauthorised use of this website may give rise to a claim for damages and/or be a criminal offence.   
7\. From time to time this website may also include links to other websites. These links are provided for your convenience to provide further information. They do not signify that we endorse the website(s). We have no responsibility for the content of the linked website(s).   
8\. Your use of this website and any dispute arising out of such use of the website is subject to the laws of the United States. 

**Trade Marks**  
EDABOARD trademarks and trade dress may not be used in connection with any product or service that is not EDABOARD in any manner that is likely to cause confusion among customers, or in any manner that disparages or discredits EDABOARD. All other trademarks not owned by EDABOARD or its subsidiaries that appear on this site are the property of their respective owners, who may or may not be affiliated with, connected to, or sponsored by EDABOARD or its subsidiaries. 

**Membership account**  
If you use this site, you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your account and password and for restricting access to your computer, and you agree to accept responsibility for all activities that occur under your account or password. EDABOARD and its associates reserve the right to refuse service, terminate accounts, remove or edit content. 

**Posts, comments and other content**  
Visitors may post reviews, comments, and other content: and submit suggestions, ideas, comments, questions, or other information, so long as the content is not illegal, obscene, threatening, defamatory, invasive of privacy, infringing of intellectual property rights, or otherwise injurious to third parties or objectionable and does not consist of or contain software viruses, political campaigning, commercial solicitation, chain letters, mass mailings, or any form of "spam." You may not use a false e-mail address, impersonate any person or entity, or otherwise mislead as to the origin of a card or other content. EDABOARD reserves the right (but not the obligation) to remove or edit such content, but does not regularly review posted content. If you do post content or submit material, and unless we indicate otherwise, you grant EDABOARD and its associates a nonexclusive, royalty-free, perpetual, irrevocable, and fully sublicensable right to use, reproduce, modify, adapt, publish, translate, create derivative works from, distribute, and display such content throughout the world in any media. You represent and warrant that you own or otherwise control all of the rights to the content that you post: that the content is accurate: that use of the content you supply does not violate this policy and will not cause injury to any person or entity: and that you will indemnify EDABOARD has the right but not the obligation to monitor and edit or remove any activity or content. EDABOARD takes no responsibility and assumes no liability for any content posted by you or any third party. 

**Applicable Law and Disputes**  
By visiting EDABOARD, you agree that the laws of the United States of America, without regard to principles of conflict of laws, will govern these Conditions and any dispute of any sort that might arise between you and EDABOARD or its associates. Any dispute relating in any way to your visit to EDABOARD shall be submitted to confidential arbitration in the United States.

 **Privacy Policy**  
This privacy policy sets out how WTWH Media, LLC uses and protects any information that you give EDABOARD when you use this website. EDABOARD is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. EDABOARD may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. 

**What we collect**  
We may collect the following information:  
* nickname  
* contact information including email address  
* select topical interest information

**What we do with the information we gather**  
We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:  
* Internal record keeping.  
* We may use the information to improve our products and services.  
* We may periodically send information emails about EDABOARD and related technologies, which we think you may find interesting, using the email address which you have provided.

We use personal information to process your requests or transactions, provide you with products and services, and inform you about other products or services we think will be of interest. Certain registration information on premium content is shared with our business partners. For example some access to WTWH or other vendors data / content requires user registration to download or access information. Also, we use the information we collect to:

* contact you for administrative purposes or provide you with customer service  
* complete transactions requested by you  
* respond to any questions, problems or complaints, or request feedback  
* organize the Site and its various services and activities to better serve you and customize or develop our products and services  
* send you emails or other communications containing information about products and services that you have requested

Personal information provided on our sites may be linked together or merged with other personal information we obtain about you so that we may better understand your needs and inform you about our products or services and those of our business partners. In addition, if we receive personal information from third parties with whom we have business relationships, we may combine this information with the other personal information we maintain about you. In either case, this Policy governs this information.

**Disclosure of Information**  
We share personal information with third-party vendors who assist us in performing internal functions necessary to operate our business. These functions may include, for example, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance and processing payment transactions. In all cases we limit the information shared with our third-party vendors to that which is necessary to carry out those functions.

We also disclose personal information when we believe it is appropriate to comply with the law (e.g., a lawful subpoena, warrant or court order); to enforce or apply this Policy or our other policies or agreements; to initiate, render, bill and collect for amounts owed to us; to protect our or our users’ rights, property or safety; to protect our users from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful use of, our Site; or if we reasonably believe that an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person requires disclosure of communications or justifies disclosure of records without delay.

In addition, information about our users, including personally identifiable information, may be disclosed as part of any merger, acquisition, debt financing or sale of company assets, as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership in which personally identifiable information could be transferred to third parties as one of our business assets.

**Security**  
We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

**How we use cookies**  
Some information is automatically collected, such as your computer’s Internet Protocol (IP) address, operating system and browser type and the time and date of your visit. This information is collected through the use of “cookies.” Cookies are small files that are stored on your computer by a Web site to give you a unique identification.

We also use cookies on our Site to keep track of services you have used, to record registration information regarding your login name and password, to ensure you do not repeatedly see advertisements, to record your user preferences and to keep you logged into the sites.

Additionally, we use, and allow third parties to use, various Web technologies on the sites to monitor the effectiveness of advertising or for other legitimate purposes.

We use third parties, called third-party ad servers or network advertisers, to deliver ads to you on our behalf. These third-party ad servers may use cookies or other technology to collect non-personally identifiable information about your visits to our sites in order to use it to present advertisements that may be of interest to you.

**Controlling your personal information**  
We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

If you have any questions or concerns about the WTWH online policy for the Design World website or its implementation you may contact us at webmaster@wtwhmedia.com.

Updates & Effective Date  
From time to time, we may update this privacy notice. We will notify you about material changes in the way we treat personally identifiable information by placing a notice on our site. We encourage you to periodically check back and review this policy so that you always will know what information we collect, how we use it, and to whom we disclose it.

The Privacy Notice posted on this site was updated on or about October 22, 2013
